# **Vishal Mantri**

Email: vishalmantri22@gmail.com Phone: 9916102832

Summary
---------

Product Manager with knack of researching, planning, executing and launching product features. Experience in executing the road map, market strategy for the constantly evolving product. Skilled in inter department communication.

Lead a team of Test Engineers in previous incarnation.

Experience	

## 1. FactSet Research (Sept 2017 - Present) Product Specialist - II

Portware Enterprise is the state of art Execution Management system which is used by world's top hedge funds. I am responsible for the product enhancements and client's request implementation for the core part of the product. I worked on the feature enhancements of the Configuration management, Positions Management and Trader Alerts, with bug releases for the stock buy and sell operations which included the process, flow design and GUI design.

#### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Execution of road-map strategy for feature release and bug fix releases for the quarterly and monthly cadences.
- Active member in redesigning of the Product into web-based technologies.
- Proficient in churning wireframes and mockups.
- Wrote Specifications and design notes from the client's request.
- Specification, acceptance criteria, user request research and impact analysis for the product features.
- Backlog Management and prioritization of work. Demos to the Stakeholder.
- Supporting the agile team in the capacity of Product Owner and Scrum Master.
- Analyze application logs and metrics for ascertaining various assumptions and data for upcoming feature requests.

## 2. Computer Sciences Corporation (now DXC.Technology ) ( July 2010 - Sept 2017 ) Professional - II Product Test

Domain: BFSI, Insurance

**Technologies:** JAVA, DB2, Sun Solaris, ETL Testing, Selenium, NFC(Near field Communication), OTA(Over the air), Net 4.0, MS SQL, SOAP, Windows Server 2008 R2, HSM, IBM MQ, SOA, Selenium, TestNG

**Roles & Responsibilities:** Test Lead, exercised Integration testing, functional testing, regression testing. Automation Testing using Selenium and SOAP UI, Reported the Defect report, root cause analysis and testing the Chip Data. Test Artifacts development. Review process, handling sub ordinates. Installation of released code.

Worked on the following projects

Workers Compensation Team – Client: Cincinnati Insurance Company

**Workers Compensation Testing-** Cincinnati Insurance Company's one of the business line is workers compensation, in which they insure Employers against the compensation of employees. An Online application issues the Policy.

Internet Common Environment team - Client: Visa

**Proximity** - Visa Contactless payment system, uses NFC, OTA technology to process payments via cell phones. It requires establishment of secure channels between user devices to Visa servers using dedicated cryptology

Involved in analyzing the requirements, developing comprehensive test plan, strategies. Build Test Cases and execute them.

### 3. Torry Harris Business Solutions ( Sept 2007 - July 2010 ) Software Engineer

**Domain: Telecom** 

Technology Involved: Java, Oracle 9i, Apache Tomcat, Linux, IBM Web-Sphere, Sun Solaris.

#### Roles & Responsibilities:

Involved in the walkthroughs and brainstorming sessions during the design phase, prepared documentation of the Test cases for the components, Performed required testing and report generation for Impact Analysis. Exercised System Integration Testing, System Testing

Developed Testing artifacts, System Testing, ETL Testing, Database Testing, Automated Test Cases using 'SAHI', Installation of release packages

Developed several **Shell** scripts to help testing procedures.

Worked in **Mentis**, which is a Fraud Detection System (JAVA Based) that monitors the calls and the subscriber payments of the customers and recommends the actions to be taken in case any fraud is detected, and in **Centralized Decisioning** which acts as intelligent system, which helps users to retain the customers with the suitable offers based on their usage. I was involved in number of Testing Procedures like System Testing, PAT (Pre Acceptance Testing), Performance testing, Regression Testing, UAT (User Acceptance Testing), PIT (Project Integration Testing) and Release Testing

Worked on the following projects in **Centralized Decisioning** 

Worked on Centralized Decisioning, project from Orange (UK) – CD provided user a Interface which helps them to decide for the deals to be made to customers to retain, offer more products etc, in turn helps to generate revenue and stabilise the customer base.

Worked on the following projects in Mentis

Worked on "FIMS (Fraud Incident Management System)", project from Orange (UK) – FIMS provides enough information to integrate existing VB based FCMS system into Mentis front-end. Along with this, it also provides details about migration of data into new format requested by fraud users, decommission of un used data items and tables and details about new data items in terms of new table structure

Worked on "Redefine Cell Id", project from Orange (UK) –

This project is intended to change the way Orange bespoke, in-house developed systems use Cell ID and to bring their design into line with 3GPP and GSM specifications. Systems will cover all live, test and development systems. This project will deliver enhancement to OUK systems to ensure that Orange's numerical method of cell identification is unique and expandable. It will change from using "Cell identity" to "Cell Global Identifier" as a unique reference.

Balsamiq, Microsoft Visio, Excel, Jira, Java, Python, Test Management tools, SQL, SOAP UI.

Certificates & Awards		
<ul> <li>Best Performance Award</li> <li>ICAgile - Agile Product Ownership</li> <li>Digital Product Management : Modern Fundamentals ( Darden School of Business)</li> <li>Consistent Top Performer</li> </ul>		
Education		
B.Tech ( Electrical Engineering ) - Dehradun Institute of Technology, Dehradun		

Visa \_\_\_\_\_

B1 US Visa